VINIT KUMAR

 $http://vinitkumar.me \\ vinit.kumar@changer.nl \\ +91-8554862210$

Summary

I am a highly motivated, self driven web developer with skills in technologies such as Python, Django, JavaScript, Ruby, Postgresql, MongoDB, Node.js, Git among others.

I favour standards based development and follow a disciplined approach to programming. I take pride and ownership in the products I work. I constantly work hard on upgrading my skills and knowledge in my area of expertise. I try to be platform/Language/framework agnostic due to which I am able to pick up technologies pretty quickly and get productive in short time.

EDUCATION

B.E Civil Engineering

Sep 2012

Birla Institute of Technology, Mesra

Career History

Software Engineer, Changer, Pune

Feb 2013 - Present

- Full time developer building Socialschools(http://socialschools.nl) which is a safe and secure Social Network committed to improve the communication and lives of people involved in Schools. I lead the Frontend Development of Socialschools along with work on the backend layers (mostly Django/Postgres). I also take care of any websites/CMS that is built for Socialschools.
- Along with Socialschools, I am the Lead developer for our service based offerings based on Django and Django-cms.
- I enjoy problem solving and both of the above products give me enough opportunities to do so.

Freelance Web Developer, gadgetizor.com and digitizor.com

Summer 2011 - Jan 2013

• Worked on the design and scaling of wordpress based high traffic sites mentioned above.

Chrome Extension Developer, Worked on a E-Commerce based Chrome Extension and a official extension of Coderwall.com coderwall.com/api Sep 2012-Nov 2012

- Developed a full stack e-commerce based chrome Extension.
- Developed the Official Chrome Extension for Coderwall.com.

SKILLS

Programming: Python, HTML5/CSS3, JavaScript, AngularJS, CoffeeScript, Jquery, LATEX, BackBoneJS, PostgreSQL

Operating Systems: OS X, Linux, Windows

IMPORTANT LINKS

Github Profile: http://github.com/vinitkumar

Linkedin Profile: http://in.linkedin.com/in/vinitatlinkedin/

LEADERSHIP ACTIVITIES

Administrator, In-Charge: Linux User Group, (Bit Mesra)

June 2011 - May 2012

Adminstrator: Web and DC server, (Bit Mesra)

June 2011- May 2012

Blog

Gotchacode Tech-blog covering topics related to web and Open Source. www.qotchacode.com